Mangetsu Dormitory
مسكن مانغيتسو
Man
مان
getsu
غيتسو
Dormitory
مسكن
Mangetsu
مانغيتسو
Oh, you must be Ohkuma Minoru-san.
لا بدّ أنّك أوكوما مينورو-سان
Most of the other students will start moving into the dorm tomorrow.
ستبدأ معظم التّلميذات الأخريات بالانتقال إلى المسكن غداً
I'll give you a quick tour of the facilities today, though.
لكن سآخذكِ في جولة سريعة حول المنشآت اليوم
Get some rest for now. You must be awfully tired.
نالي قسطاً من الرّاحة حاليّاً. لا بدّ وأنّكِ مُرهَقة
Yes, ma'am.
حاضرة
Oh, wow!
!مذهل
A tiger beetle. It's even prettier than the picture!
!خنفساء النّمر. إنّها أجمل من الصّورة حتّى
A peacock butterfly, too?
فراشة طاووس أيضاً؟
I've never seen one before!
!لم أرَ واحدة من قبل
Wait!
!لحظة
Y-Yes, ma'am!
!حاضرة
Self-introductions
تعريف ذاتيّ
I'm Akebi Komichi, seat number 1.
أنا أكيبي كوميتشي، المقعد رقم 1
Episode Five I Want to Learn Lots
الحلقة الخامسة أريد تعلّم الكثير
A ladybug?
دعسوقة؟
It's a weevil.
إنّها خنفساء القطن
Their long necks make them unique.
عنقها الطويل يجعلها فريدة
Akebi Komichi...
...أكيبي كوميتشي
Last time, she had a Schlegel's green tree frog.
في المرّة السّابقة، كان معها ضفدع شجر شليغيل أخضر
And today, she's playing with a weevil.
واليوم تلعب بخنفساء قطن
What?!
!ماذا؟
Oh, no!
!يا للهول
No way, no way! I can't stand this sort of thing!
!مستحيل، مستحيل! لا أتحمّل مثل هذه الأشياء
Should I go get a teacher ASAP?
هل ينبغي أن أحضر مُعلّمة في أسرع وقت؟
A Japanese rat snake.
أفعى جرذ يابانيّة
It looked this way!
!نظرتْ إلى هنا
It's gonna bite you!
!سوف تعضّك
It's not even scary.
ليست مُخيفة حتّى
Are you lost?
هل تهتِ؟
Isn't it cute?
أليست ظريفة؟
Ohkuma Minoru-san?
أوكوما مينورو-سان؟
Uh, yeah...
...أجل
She has eyes like a seal's.
لديها عينان كعينَي الفقمة
Let's take it somewhere quiet.
لنأخذها إلى مكان هادئ ما
Yeah... Let's.
نعم... هيّا بنا
This area should be safe.
ينبغي أن تكون هذه المنطقة آمنة
Ohkuma-san, is that your own cage?
أوكوما-سان، أهذا قفصكِ؟
You actually bring it to school?
أتحضرينه إلى المدرسة حقّاً؟
Yes! Because you never know what you'll find, or where!
!أجل! لأنّكِ لا تعلمين ما قد تجدين أو أين
Japanese rat snakes are interesting because their colors and patterns vary
أفاعي الجرذ اليابانيّة مثيرة للاهتمام بسبب تنوّع ألوانها وأشكالها
depending on the region.
بحسب المنطقة
Wow, really?! I never knew that!
!حقّاً؟! لم أكن أعلم ذلك
I've seen them swimming like pros in the river before!
!رأيتُها تسبح باحترافيّة في النّهر من قبل
That's a priceless sighting!
!هذا مشهد لا يُقدّر بثمن
And not long ago, when I was walking in the woods,
ومنذ مدّة ليست بطويلة، عندما كنتُ ،أمشي في الغابة
I bumped into a vine wrapped around a branch.
واصطدمتُ بكرمة ملفوفة حول غصن شجرة
And that vine was...
...وتلك الكرمة كانت
Wait, you mean...
...لحظة، تقصدين
A Japanese rat snake!
!أفعى جرذ يابانيّة
Incredible!
!مدهش
What's that, Ohkuma-san?
ما هذا يا أوكوما-سان؟
My research notebook.
دفتر بحثي
I write down unique characteristics of living things I see,
،أدوّن الصّفات المُميّزة للكائنات الحيّة التي أراها
and the details of how I found them, every day.
وتفاصيل إيجادها كلّ يوم
Your stories gave me valuable information.
مدّتني قصصكِ بمعلومات قيّمة
I do that, too!
!أنا أفعل ذلك أيضاً
I always write down things I notice in a notebook.
دائماً ما أدوّن ما ألاحظه في مذكّرة
So you're also interested in the observation of living things?
أنتِ مهتمّة إذاً بمراقبة الكائنات الحيّة؟
Class 1-3
الصفّ 3-1
See?
انظري
Class 1-3?
الصفّ 3-1؟
I write notes about everyone in our class.
أدوّن ملاحظات عن الجميع في صفّنا
I was just so happy to have classmates, since I've never had them before.
،كنتُ سعيدة جدّاً بالتعرّف على زميلات في الصفّ بما أنّني لم أكن أعرف أحداً من قبل
Class 1-3
الصفّ 3-1
I want to learn lots about everyone... but...
...أريد تعلّم الكثير عن الجميع... لكن
I can't always find the right timing to talk to them, so...
لا أستطيع دوماً إيجاد التّوقيت المناسب ...للتكلّم معهن، لذا
That's where observation comes in handy.
هنا يأتي دور المُراقبة
Learning more about someone, such as what they like and dislike,
،إنّ معرفة المزيد عن شخص ما، مثل ما يحبّه ويكرهه
could help you out in future conversations.
قد تساعدكِ في محادثات مستقبليّة
Then let's do that together!
!لنفعل ذلك معاً إذاً
Green Tea
شاي أخضر
Red Bean Soup
حساء فاصولياء حمراء
Rich Corn Potage
شوربة ذرة غنيّة
Warm
دافئ
According to my observations,
،وفقاً لملاحظاتي
our subject appears right here every morning.
تظهر مادّة بحثنا هنا في كلّ صباح
Hiraiwa Hotaru-san...
...هيرايوا هوتارو-سان
I haven't really talked to her very much yet.
لم أتكلّم معها كثيراً بعد
What's she going to get?
على ماذا ستحصل؟
C-Could it be...
...هـ-هل يُعقل
Hmm... I'm surprised she's going for the red bean soup on the top shelf.
أنا متفاجئة من أنّها تهدف لحساء الفاصولياء الحمراء في الرفّ الأعلى
She's quite a challenger.
إنّها مُحبّة للتحدّيات
Will she be able to purchase an item that's up so high?
هل ستتمكّن من شراء مُنتَج عالٍ إلى هذه الدّرجة؟
This is truly intriguing.
هذا مثير للفضول حقّاً
Akebi-san?
أكيبي-سان؟
Mind if I help?
هل يمكنني المساعدة؟
Now you can reach the button, right?
الآن يمكنكِ الوصول إلى الزرّ، صحيح؟
R E D B E A N S O U P
حساء فاصولياء حمراء
Made with Beans from Hokkaido
مُكوّنة من فاصولياء من هوكّايدو
C H U N K Y
.قد يختلف المُنتَج الفعليّ عن الصّورة
Actual product may differ from image.
حساء فاصولياء حمراء
R E D B E A N S O U P
مُكوّنة من فاصولياء من هوكّايدو
Made with Beans from Hokkaido
.قد يختلف المُنتَج الفعليّ عن الصّورة
C H U N K Y
حساء فاصولياء حمراء
Actual product may differ from image.
مُكوّنة من فاصولياء من هوكّايدو
R E D B E A N S O U P
.قد يختلف المُنتَج الفعليّ عن الصّورة
Made with Beans from Hokkaido
حساء فاصولياء حمراء
C H U N K Y
مُكوّنة من فاصولياء من هوكّايدو
Actual product may differ from image.
.قد يختلف المُنتَج الفعليّ عن الصّورة
R E D B E A N S O U P
حساء فاصولياء حمراء
Made with Beans from Hokkaido
مُكوّنة من فاصولياء من هوكّايدو
C H U N K Y
.قد يختلف المُنتَج الفعليّ عن الصّورة
Actual product may differ from image.
حساء فاصولياء حمراء
R E D B E A N S O U P
مُكوّنة من فاصولياء من هوكّايدو
Made with Beans from Hokkaido
.قد يختلف المُنتَج الفعليّ عن الصّورة
Yay!
!مرحى
I do that for my little sister a lot, too.
أفعل هذا لأختي الصّغيرة كثيراً أيضاً
Thank you very much.
شكراً جزيلاً لكِ
Oh, you're very welcome!
!على الرّحب والسّعة
You can't do that, Akebi-san.
لا يمكنك فعل ذلك يا أكيبي-سان
Observing living things means
مراقبة الأشياء الحيّة تعني
watching them from an objective viewpoint and recording what you see.
مشاهدتها من وجهة نظر موضوعيّة وتسجيل ما ترينه
You're not supposed to interfere in what you observe.
لا يُفترض بكِ أن تتدخّلي فيما تلاحظينه
Oh, yeah. Sorry.
أجل. آسفة
It's so shiny...
...إنّها مُتألّقة جدّاً
I got some interesting data. Akebi Komichi is...
...حصلتُ على بيانات مثيرة للاهتمام. أكيبي كوميتشي
• Akebi Komichi is the active type!!
!!أكيبي كوميتشي هي من النّوع النّشط *
Plays with her little sister often? Lifted Hiraiwa Hotaru-san like she weighed nothing Has quite a bit of muscle
كثيراً ما تلعب مع أختها الصّغيرة؟ رفعتْ هيرايوا هوتارو-سان كما لو أنّها بلا وزن لديها قوّة عضليّة
Hiraiwa Hotaru-chan
هيرايوا هوتارو-تشان
Looks a bit like Kao
تشبه كاو قليلاً
Onee-chan!
!أونيه-تشان
Cute
ظريفة
Has soft, pretty hair. Smells nice.
.لديها شعر جميل وناعم .رائحة زكيّة
Oh, Hotaru-chan.
هوتارو-تشان
You finally succeeded in your challenge? Way to go!
!نجحتِ أخيراً في تحدّيكِ؟ أحسنتِ
I'll work hard so I can buy it on my own next time.
سأعمل بجدّ وذلك كي أستطيع شراءها من تلقاء نفسي في المرّة المقبلة
You could call it spying.
يمكنكِ اعتبار ذلك تجسّساً
You erase your own presence in order to secretly observe your subject.
تُخفين وجودكِ من أجل مراقبة مادّة بحثكِ بشكل سرّي
To ensure you don't miss even a moment's change...
...لضمان عدم تفويت أيّ لحظة
What did you call me out here for?
لماذا استدعيتني إلى هنا؟
Washio Hitomi-san!
!واشيو هيتومي-سان
She's talking to a girl from Class 1.
إنّها تتكلّم مع فتاة من الصفّ 1
How do you know that?
ما أدراكِ بذلك؟
I live in the Mangetsu Dorm.
أقيم في مسكن مانغيتسو
It looks like they're talking about something,
،يبدو وكأنّهما تتحدّثان عن شيء ما
but I can't hear them from here.
لكن لا أستطيع سماعهما من هنا
It's not just their conversation that can tell us what's going on.
ليس بالضرورة أن تكون محادثتهما هي ما يخبرنا عمّا يجري
Let's carefully observe their body language, expressions, and the situation.
لنراقب لغة جسدهما وتعابير وجهيهما وظرفهما بدقّة
Stare...
...تحديق
What could they be talking about?
عمّاذا تتكلّمان يا تُرى؟
N-Nawashiro-san?!
!نـ-ناواشيرو-سان؟
Shh!
!صه
It's always so easy to tell where Akebi-chan is.
من السّهل دوماً معرفة مكان أكيبي-تشان
Hey. I can hear you.
أنتِما. أسمعكما
Heya, Hitomi-chan... and...
...مرحباً يا هيتومي-تشان... و
Uh... I...
...المعذرة... أنا
Hi, Tanabe-san.
مرحباً يا تانابي-سان
I'm sorry, was I interrupting?
أنا آسفة، هل تمّت مقاطعتي؟
No, actually, this is perfect.
لا، في الواقع، هذا مثاليّ
She says she wants to be your friend, Yasuko.
تقول بأنّها تريد أن تكون صديقتك يا ياسكو
And...
...و
Just what were you two doing?
ماذا كنتما تفعلان بالضبط؟
• Akebi Komichi is the active type!!
!!أكيبي كوميتشي هي من النّوع النّشط *
Plays with her little sister often? Lifted Hiraiwa Hotaru-san like she weighed nothing Has quite a bit of muscle
كثيراً ما تلعب مع أختها الصّغيرة؟ رفعتْ هيرايوا هوتارو-سان كما لو أنّها بلا وزن لديها قوّة عضليّة
Akebi Komichi is conspicuous!!
!أكيبي كوميتشي مُلفِتة
Dirt on her shoes. Gets sidetracked easily?
.حذاؤها متّسخ تحيد عن الطريق بسهولة؟
Nawashiro-san
ناواشيرو-سان
Washio-san
واشيو-سان
Washio-san and Nawashiro-san are good friends!
واشيو-سان وناواشيرو-سان !صديقتان حميمتان
Washio-san is very tall
واشيو-سان طويلة جدّاً
So cool!
!رائعة للغاية
Lives in the dorm. Maybe I can visit someday?
.تعيش في المسكن ربّما أستطيع الزيارة يوماً ما؟
Uh, Ohkuma-san, did we really need to hide ourselves this well?
أوكوما-سان، هل توجّب علينا حقّاً إخفاء أنفسنا بهذا الحرص؟
You stand out no matter where you are,
،أنتِ مُلفتة أينما حللتِ
so we might as well conceal ourselves from our subject completely.
لذا علينا إخفاء أنفسنا من مادّة بحثنا كلّياً
O-Okay...
...حـ-حسناً
Oh, here comes someone.
هناك أحد قادم
It's Shijou Riona-san.
إنّها شيجو ريونا-سان
I can't see very well from in here.
لا أستطيع الرّؤية جيّداً من هنا
Is she searching for something?
هل تبحث عن شيء ما؟
Huh?
ماذا؟
A sandwich?! That looks so good!
!شطيرة؟! تبدو لذيذة جدّاً
I-It's just, uh...
...هـ-هذا فقط
I missed breakfast today because I overslept,
،فوّتُّ الفطور اليوم. لأنّني غططتُ في النوم
so my mom wrapped this up for me...
...لذا لفّت أمّي هذه لي
Um... Ohkuma-san?
المعذرة... أوكوما-سان؟
I-I'm so sorry!
!أ-أنا آسفة جدّاً
• Akebi Komichi is the active type!!
!!أكيبي كوميتشي هي من النّوع النّشط *
Plays with her little sister often? Lifted Hiraiwa Hotaru-san like she weighed nothing Has quite a bit of muscle
كثيراً ما تلعب مع أختها الصّغيرة؟ رفعتْ هيرايوا هوتارو-سان كما لو أنّها بلا وزن لديها قوّة عضليّة
Akebi Komichi is conspicuous!!
!أكيبي كوميتشي مُلفِتة
Dirt on her shoes. Gets sidetracked easily?
.حذاؤها متّسخ تحيد عن الطريق بسهولة؟
Akebi Komichi is extremely ticklish!!
!!أكيبي كوميتشي سريعة الدغدغة
Shijou-san's chest is soft and warm like the bunnies in the pen
صدر شيجو-سان ناعم ودافئ كالأرانب في الحظيرة
Shijou-san Prefers bread with breakfast!!
شيجو-سان !!تفضّل الخبز مع الفطور
That sandwich looked really good... I always get hungry around this time of day, too
...بدت تلك الشّطيرة لذيذة جدّاً دائماً ما أجوع في هذه الفترة من اليوم أيضاً
This isn't going very well, is it?
لا يسير هذا الأمر على ما يُرام، صحيح؟
But I've still been able to gather some very interesting data,
لكن ما زلتُ قادرة على جمع بعض ،البيانات المثيرة للاهتمام
so it all worked out.
لذا أفلحت الأمور
Wow, you're really good at drawing, Ohkuma-san!
!أنتِ بارعة حقّاً في الرّسم يا أوكوما-سان
S-Since I keep a research notebook every day,
،بـ-بما أنّني أحتفظ بمذكّرة بحث في كلّ يوم
I naturally picked up the ability.
اكتسبتُ القدرة بشكل طبيعيّ
That's so impressive!
!هذا مدهش للغاية
What about you?
ماذا عنكِ؟
Are you finished drawing it?
هل انتهيتِ من رسمها؟
I get it.
I get it.فهمت
Drawing it in a simplified manner
رسمها بطريقة مُبسّطة
can actually enhance the subject's unique characteristics.
يمكن أن يعزّز الصّفات المُميّزة لمادّة البحث
Another good call.
قرار جيّد آخر
That feels nice.
يا له من شعور لطيف
Yes, it's a very nice breeze.
أجل، إنّه نسيم عليل
Since we're always stuck at our desks during class time,
،بما أنّنا ملتصقتان دوماً بمقعدنا أثناء الحصّة
we're lucky to have a chance to observe in this kind of setting.
نحن محظوظتان بامتلاكنا فرصة للمراقبة في مثل هذا المكان
Really?
حقّاً؟
You get a better look at people's hobbies, preferences, and natural behaviors.
حريّ بكِ أن تنظري إلى هوايات النّاس وتفضيلاتهم وسلوكهم الطبيعيّ
For example... let me see...
...على سبيل المثال... دعيني أرى
Look there.
انظري هناك
Togano Mai-san.
توغانو ماي-سان
The fact that she can draw so many different species of birds so distinctly
حقيقة قدرتها على رسم الكثير من أنواع الطيور المختلفة بهذه الدقّة
tells me that she's very fond of birds.
تجعلني أدرك بأنّها مولعة بالطيور
Wow, you're right.
معكِ حقّ
I hope I can have a good chat with her sometime.
آمل أن أتمكّن من مُحادثتها جيّداً يوماً ما
Minakami Riri-san.
ميناكامي ريري-سان
Is she done drawing, too?
هل انتهت من الرّسم أيضاً؟
I think it's more likely that she's looking for something to draw.
أعتقد من المُرجّح أكثر بأنّها تبحث عن شيء ترسمه
The way she patiently searches for prey
الطريقة التي تبحث فيها عن الفريسة بصبر
reminds me of a black leopard, a master of hunting.
تذكّرني بالنّمر الأسود، معلّم الصّيد
You're right!
!معكِ حقّ
Or... maybe she just doesn't like big crowds of people, like me.
أو... لعلّها لا تحبّ الازدحامات الكبيرة للناس مثلي
You've spent a lot of time watching everyone, huh, Ohkuma-san?
قضيتِ كثيراً من الوقت وأنتِ تشاهدين الجميع، أليس كذلك يا أوكوما-سان؟
I-I wouldn't say "everyone"...
"لـ-ليس "الجميع
The living thing that currently interests me the most is...
...أكثر شيء يهمّني حاليّاً هو
Is?
هو...؟
Um...
...في الواقع
Akebi-san, there you are.
أكيبي-سان، ها أنتِ ذي
Hey, Ohkuma-san, you're really good at drawing!
!أوكوما-سان، أنتِ بارعة حقّاً في الرّسم
She really is!
!إنّها كذلك بالفعل
Yeah, you captured its unique characteristics really well.
!أجل، التقطتِ سِماتها الفريدة جيّداً
Wow, Ohkuma-san, you're red as an apple.
أوكوما-سان، وجهكِ أحمر كتفّاحة
An apple!
!تفّاحة
You're right!
!معكِ حقّ
How cute!
!كم هذا ظريف
Class 1-3
الصفّ 3-1
Roubai Academy 5
أكاديميّة روباي 5
Akebi-san, didn't something feel strange to you a moment ago?
أكيبي-سان، ألم يبدُ شيء غريباً بالنسبة لكِ قبل مدّة؟
Strange how?
غريب من أيّ ناحية؟
Like someone was watching us...
...كما لو أنّ شخصاً كان يراقبنا
I see.
هكذا إذاً
So yeah, that happened. I laughed my butt off.
هذا ما حدث. انفجرتُ ضحكاً
Really?
حقّاً؟
I knew it. The one watching was my roommate, Tougeguchi-san.
توقّعت. من يراقبني كانت زميلتي في الغرفة، توغيغوتشي-سان
I had no idea there was someone else like me.
لم أكن أعلم أنّه يوجد شخص آخر مثلي
See you tomorrow.
أراكِ غداً
But why would...
...لكن لماذا
Akebi Komichi
أكيبي كوميتشي
Today was another bust.
فشل آخر اليوم
I just never get the chance.
لم أحظَ بفرصة أبداً
I mean, an elite all-girls school in the country
أعني ينبغي لمدرسة فتيات نخبة في البلد
should be full o' girls who ain't that popular.
أن تكون مليئة بالفتيات اللّواتي لا يحظين بشعبيّة
But they're all so pretty, and they're always with their brilliant buddies...
لكن جميعهن حسناوات ودائماً ما يرافقن صديقات متألّقات
I thought I was the only one on her side!
!ظننتُ أنّني الوحيدة التي كنتُ في صفّها
Akebi Komichi, you...
...أكيبي كوميتشي، أنتِ
traitor!
!خائنة
Man, nothin' makes me feel better than a good scream!
!لا شيء يُشعرني براحة أكثر من صرخة قويّة
Akebi...san?
أكيبي... سان؟
And... Ohkuma-san?
و... أوكوما-سان؟
Wait, th-this ain't what it looks like!
!لحظة، ا-الأمر ليس كما يبدو
I wasn't sayin' anything about you, Akebi-san... um... I mean, uh...
لم أكن أقول شيئاً عنكِ يا أكيبي-سان ...المعذرة... أعني
This...
...هذا
Why's a pretty girl like her hafta take the test for this school?
لماذا على فتاة جميلة مثلها أن تخضع لاختبار لهذه المدرسة؟
It's gonna kill my middle school debut.
هذا سيُفسِد أوّل ظهوري الأوّل في المدرسة الإعداديّة
What am I gonna do if this doesn't get better before the exam?
ماذا سأفعل إذا لم يتحسّن هذا قبل الامتحان؟
I forgot my handkerchief...
...نسيتُ منديلي
I'm hopeless.
أنا بائسة
Here.
خذي
Use this.
استعملي هذا
Th-Thanks...
...شـ-شكراً
Why are you using a restroom so far from everything?
لماذا تستخدمين دورة مياه بعيدة عن كلّ شيء؟
Huh? Er... What about you?
ماذا؟ ماذا عنكِ؟
I just feel kinda uneasy in crowded places.
أشعر بالتوتّر في الأماكن المزدحمة
There is a god...
...هناك إله
A kind one...
...لطيف
Akebi Komichi
أكيبي كوميتشي
"Akebi Komichi."
"أكيبي كوميتشي"
The exam will begin shortly.
سيبدأ الامتحان قريباً
I gotta run!
!عليّ أن أركض
Please report to your designated classroom.
الرّجاء الحضور إلى صفوفكن المُخصّصة
Hey, hang on!
!مهلاً لحظة
What d'ya want me to do with this?!
!ماذا تريدينني أن أفعل بهذا؟
Keep it until the next time I see you!
!احتفظي به حتّى أراكِ في المرّة المقبلة
Next time? What does she mean by that?
المرّة المقبلة؟ ماذا قصدت بذلك؟
This is just the entrance exam venue.
هذا مجرّد موقع لامتحانات القبول
There's no guarantee we'll...
...لا يوجد ما يضمن بأنّنا
Was she tellin' me I have to pass?!
!لمَ تخبرني أنّ عليّ أن أنجح؟
This is the handkerchief I lent to you before the exam!
!هذا هو المنديل الّذي أعرتُكِ إيّاه قبل الامتحان
I-I'm sorry!
!أ-أنا آسفة
I wanted to return it all this time...
...أردتُ إعادته طوال هذا الوقت
I'm so happy!
!أنا سعيدة للغاية
So that girl was you, Tougeguchi-san!
!إذاً كانت تلك الفتاة أنتِ يا توغيغوتشي-سان
All this time, I wondered who it was!
!طوال هذا الوقت، تساءلتُ من كانت
I'm so happy we got into this school together!
!أنا سعيدة جدّاً لأنّنا التحقنا بهذه المدرسة معاً
Thanks!
!شكراً
I just didn't recognize you in the uniform. It makes you look so different.
لم أعرفكِ بالزيّ الرّسمي فحسب. هذا يجعلكِ مختلفة كثيراً
I never thought the girl in the silly PJs
لم أتوقّع أبداً أن تظهر الفتاة بالبيجاما السّخيفة
would show up in a sailor uniform on the first day, either.
بزيّ بحّارة رسميّ في اليوم الأوّل أيضاً
Still...
...رغم ذلك
It's because I met Akebi-san and realized someone else was as nervous as me
لأنّني التقيتُ بأكيبي-سان وأدركتُ أنّ شخصاً آخر غيري كان متوتّراً مثلي
that I was able to stick with the exam.
تمكّنتُ من الالتزام بالامتحان
What do we do now, Ohkuma-san? The subject caught us again!
!ماذا نفعل الآن يا أوكوما-سان؟ كشفَتنا مادّة البحث ثانية
At this point, you might as well call it a talent.
يمكن أن نسمّي هذا بالموهبة في حالة كهذه
Well, I'm gonna go now.
حسناً، سوف أذهب الآن
Okay.
حسناً
Akebi Komichi...san!
!أكيبي كوميتشي... سان
I-I'm...
...أ-أنا
I'm glad to know ya!
!أنا مسرورة بمعرفتك
Same to you!
!كذلك أنا
I guess Tougeguchi-san was looking for the right moment to talk to you all along, too.
أعتقد أنّ توغيغوتشي-سان كانت تبحث عن اللّحظة المناسبة لتتكلّم وتنسجم معكِ أيضاً
She should have said something to me sooner!
!كان ينبغي أن تخبرني بذلك في وقت مُسبَق
There were some blunders and accidents along the way,
،وقعتْ بعض الأخطاء والحوادث أثناء ذلك
but I guess we can say our observation mission was an overall success.
لكن أعتقد يمكننا القول بأنّ مهمّة المراقبة خاصّتنا نجحت بالمُجمَل
Yeah!
!أجل
I was really happy to learn some new things about our classmates!
كنتُ سعيدة حقّاً بتعلّم أشياء جديدة !عن زميلاتنا في الصفّ
Thanks!
!شكراً
I never thought I'd have a chance to talk to you this way,
لم أتوقّع أبداً بأنّني سأحظى بفرصة ،للتكلّم معكِ بهذا الشكل
so observing with you has been a great experience for me.
لذا فالمراقبة معكِ كانت تجربة عظيمة لي
So I...
...لذلك أنا
want to thank you, too.
أريد أن أشكركِ أيضاً
You know...
...في الحقيقة
I always wanted a chance to talk to you, too, Ohkuma-san.
لطالما أردتُ أن أحصل على فرصة للتكلّم معكِ أيضاً يا أوكوما-سان
I wondered why you were always secretly watching me.
لطالما تساءلتُ لماذا كنتِ تراقبينني سرّاً
What?! Y-You knew about that?
!ماذا؟! كـ-كنتِ تعلمين بذلك؟
But I got to learn lots of things I didn't know about you today.
لكن تعلّمتُ كثيراً من الأشياء التي لم أكن أعرفها عنكِ اليوم
You know a lot about living things, and you're good at drawing.
الكثير عن الكائنات الحيّة وعن براعتكِ في الرّسم
There's still a lot I don't know,
،ما زال هناك الكثير ممّا لا أعرفه
so I hope you'll teach me lots more from now on.
لذا آمل أن تعلّميني الكثير من الآن فصاعداً
Would you like to observe insects together next time?
هل ترغبين أن نراقب الحشرات معاً في المرّة المقبلة؟
Yes! Yes!
!أجل! أجل
Yay! Thank you!
!مرحى! شكراً لكِ
Akebi-san, not so tight...
...أكيبي-سان، أنتِ تخنقينني